A Finding Aid to the Dorr Bothwell Papers, 1900-2006, in the Archives of American Art AAA.bothdorr
Archives of American Art
Dorr Bothwell papers
1900-2006
AAA.bothdorr
Archives of American Art
10.6 Linear feet
The papers of California painter, printmaker, and art instructor Dorr Bothwell date from 1900-2006, and measure 10.6 linear feet. Found within the papers are biographical material, correspondence, personal business records, notes and writings, five diaries, art work and 19 sketchbooks, three scrapbooks, printed material, and photographs.
Bothwell, Dorr
Provenance
The Dorr Bothwell papers were donated in 1978 by the artist, and in 2002, 2009, and 2012 by the Dorr Bothwell Trust.
Restrictions on Access
Use of original papers requires an appointment. Use of archival audiovisual recordings with no duplicate access copy requires advance notice.
Biographical Note
Dorr Bothwell (1902-2000) worked primarily in California as a painter, printmaker, and art instructor.
Doris Bothwell was born on May 3, 1902 in San Francisco, and later changed her first name to Dorr in order to more easily enter the art business. Bothwell began her art studies in 1916 with her parents' friend Anna Valentien, a student of Rodin. Between 1921 and 1922, she studied at the California School of Fine Art, and continued her studies at the University of Oregon at Eugene. After attending the Rudolph Schaeffer School of Design in 1924, she established her own studio in San Francisco from 1924 to 1927. Also during this time Bothwell, with eight other artists opened the Modern Gallery on Montgomery Street, mounting her first solo exhibition there in 1927.
Between 1928 and 1929, Bothwell traveled to American Samoa, where she created paintings and drawings, and documented tapa (barkcloth) drawings for the Bishop Museum of Honolulu. She then spent a year of study in Europe, returning to San Diego, California in 1931 and marrying sculptor Donal Hord. Four years later, they divorced and she moved to Los Angeles where she worked for the pottery manufacturer Gladding McBean, joined the post-surrealist group around Lorser Feitelson and Helen Lundeberg and opened the Bothwell-Cooke Gallery.
Between 1936 and 1939, Bothwell worked in the mural division of the Federal Arts Project of Los Angeles, and learned the art of serigraph printing. She designed dioramas and mechanized exhibitions for the Los Angeles County Museum. In 1940 she also created murals in the Manning Coffee Restaurant in San Francisco.
After teaching color and design at the California School of Fine Art in San Francisco from 1944 to 1948, Bothwell was awarded the Abraham Rosenberg Traveling Scholarship that financed study in Paris from 1949 to the fall of 1951. In 1952 she taught textile design for mass production at the Parsons School of Design in New York City.
Returning to San Francisco, Bothwell taught again at the California School of Fine Art from 1953 to 1958, and at the San Francisco Art Institute from 1959 to 1960. From 1960 to 1961 she took a sabbatical in England and France, creating paintings for an exhibition. In 1962 she was asked to teach at the new Mendocino Art Center and she taught there until 1983. She was also asked by Ansel Adams to teach design and composition for photographers at his Yosemite Workshop summer sessions, which she did from 1964 to 1977.
From 1966 to 1967, Bothwell documented indigo dying techniques, strip weaving, and pottery in Western Nigeria and Tunisia. In 1968, she published her book, co-authored with Marlys Frey, NOTAN The Principle of Dark-Light Design. The book was reissued in 1991. Bothwell continued her travels from 1970 to 1971, when she studied 12th century enamels in England, France, and Holland, and conducted a symposium, "Notan Design," for the London Educational Authority. In 1974, she traveled to Bali, Java, and Sumatra, making a slide documentary on batik, woodcarving, and folk design.
In 1977 Bothwell moved to Joshua Tree, California, from Mendocino in Northern California, but moved back and forth between the two studio/residences until 1992 when she moved to her last residence on the desert at Apache Junction, Arizona. From 1979 to 1980, she taught composition at the Victor School of Photography in Colorado and a design course at the Women's Art Guild in Kauai, Hawaii. Following a tour of China with a watercolor artists' group in 1982, Bothwell conducted workshops at the Mendocino Art Center. In 1985, she traveled to Japan.
Dorr Bothwell died on September 24, 2000 in Fort Bragg, California.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of California painter, printmaker, and art instructor Dorr Bothwell date from 1900-2006, and measure 10.6 linear feet. Found within the papers are biographical material, correspondence, personal business records, notes and writings, five diaries, art work and 19 sketchbooks, three scrapbooks, printed material, and photographs.
Biographical material consists of biographical sketches, resumés, identity cards, award certificates, typescripts of autobiographical interviews, address books, and a file concerning UFOs, spirituality, and philosophy.
Correspondence consists of letters exchanged between Bothwell and her colleagues and friends discussing their art-related activities, travel, and birthday greetings. There are scattered letters from Ansel and Virginia Adams, Etel Adnan, Benjamin Chinn, Claire Falkenstein, and Emmy Lou Packard.
Personal business records include teaching contracts, contracts and royalty statements for the publication of Bothwell's book Notan, insurance records, income tax records, records concerning a grant from the Pollock-Krasner Foundation, estate records, card files, lists of art work, price lists, exhibition entry cards, receipts for the sale of art work, travel receipts, medical receipts, and consignment/sales records.
Notes and writings include three diaries, two travel journals, guest books, miscellaneous lists, schedules of classes for various organizations and art schools including the Ansel Adams Yosemite Workshop, typescripts of lecture notes, and miscellaneous notes. There are also scattered writings by Bothwell and others.
Seventeen sketchbooks, including several completed during Bothwell's travels, and one dated 1942 illustrated with daily drawings of her activities while preparing for World War II, are found within the papers. There are also miscellaneous drawings, collages, a serigraph It's Time for a Change, an etching by Martha Jackson, and a drawing by Charles Howard.
Three scrapbooks contain clippings, exhibition announcements and catalogs, programs, and photographs of art work. Scrapbook 3 contains materials concerning spiritualism and mysticism. Additional printed material consists of clippings, exhibition announcements and catalogs, press releases, brochures for art classes, the sale of art work, travel, and camera equipment, reproductions of art work, picture postcards, programs, books, and miscellaneous commercial business cards.
Photographs are of Bothwell, her mother and brother, her studio/residences, miscellaneous friends and colleagues including her former husband, sculptor Donal Hord, miscellaneous events, and art classes conducted by Bothwell. There are also photographs of art work by Bothwell and others, as well as numerous photographs and slides of travel various forms in nature that Bothwell would incorporate into her art work.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged as 8 series:
Series 1: Biographical Material, 1939-2001 (Box 1, 11, 13, 15; 0.6 linear feet)
Series 2: Correspondence, 1942-2002 (Box 1-3, 13; 2.3 linear feet)
Series 3: Personal Business Records, 1925-2006 (Box 3-4; 0.7 linear feet)
Series 4: Notes and Writings, 1949-1998 (Box 4, 11, 14, 15; 0.8 linear feet.)
Series 5: Art Work, 1920-1994 (Box 4-5, 11, 13, 16, 17; 1.5 linear feet)
Series 6: Scrapbooks, 1926-1979 (Box 5, 11, 12; 0.5 linear feet)
Series 7: Printed Material, 1923-2000 (Box 5-7, 12, 13; 1.8 linear feet)
Series 8: Photographs, 1900-2001 (Box 7-9, 10; 2.4 linear feet)
Adams, Ansel, 1902-1984; Adams, Virginia Best; Adnan, Etel; Chinn, Benjamen, 1921-2009; Falkenstein, Claire, 1908-1997; Howard, Charles, 1899-1978; Jackson, Martha Kellogg; Packard, Emmy Lou, 1914-; Pollock-Krasner Foundation; Art teachers--California; Artists' studios--Photographs; Awards; Collages; Contracts; Diaries; Drawings; Interviews; Lecture notes; Painters--California; Photographs; Scrapbooks; Sketchbooks; Sketches; Surrealism; Travel journals; Visitors' books; Women artists--California; World War, 1939-1945
- Biographical Material, 1939-1999; Series 1; (Box 1, 11, 13, 15; 0.6 linear feet)
  Scope and Contents note
  Biographical material consists of biographical sketches, resumés, a handwritten outline of Bothwell's teaching career, identity cards including photocopies of her passport, and student cards from Paris, award certificates, typescripts of autobiographical interviews including one concerning her travel to Samoa, and address books. The recording of Bothwell's memories of Samoa are on five sound cassettes. There is also a file concerning Unidentified Flying Objects, Spirituality, and Philosophy, containing letters, clippings, brochures, and a sheet of UFO stickers.
  - Biographical Sketches, 1978-1983, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Resumés, 1952-1993, undated; (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 2-3)
  - Outline of Teaching Career, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous Identity Cards, 1939-1992 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Membership Cards, 1958-1995, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Award Certificates, 1979-1993, undated; (Oversized Material Housed in Box 11) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Typescript of Autobiographical Interview 1, 1997, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Typescript of Autobiographical Interview 2, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Autobiographical Typescript "Straws in the Wind," An Artist's Life as Told to Bruce Levene, 1997; (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 10-11)
  - Transcript of Rudolph Schaeffer Interview, 1981 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Interview concerning Bothwell's Memories in Samoa, 1986-1999; 5 Sound cassettes (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Interview Documents concerning Bothwell's Memories in Samoa, 1986-1999; Includes 2 floppy disks. (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Transcript of Interview Concerning Bothwell's Memories of Samoa, 1986-1999; (10 folders) (Box 1, Folder 12-21)
  - Address Books, 1972, undated; (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 22-23)
  - File Concerning UFOs, Spirituality, and Philosophy, 1955-1967; (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 24-25)
  - Miscellaneous Biographical Computer Printouts, 2001 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Oversized Award Certificate from San Francisco Art Commission, 1979; from Box 1, Folder 7 (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 1939-2002; Series 2; (Box 1-3, 13; 2.3 linear feet)
  Correspondence consists of letters exchanged between Bothwell and her colleagues and friends discussing their art-related activities, travel, and birthday greetings. There are scattered letters from Ansel and Virginia Adams, Etel Adnan, Benjamin Chinn, Claire Falkenstein, and Emmy Lou Packard. Most letters from Monica Hannasch contain amusing cartoons that illustrate her messages. Two letters from Ansel Adams are signed with a smiling cartoon doodle.
  - Unidentified Correspondents, 1952-1996, undated; (3 folders) (Box 1, Folder 26-28)
  - Letters with Multiple Signatures, 1988-1995, undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Correspondents' Surnames Unknown; First Names "A" - "B,", 1956-1991, undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Correspondents' Surnames Unknown; First Names "C,", 1969-1992, undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Correspondents' Surnames Unknown; First Names "D,", 1954-1999, undated; (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 32-33)
  - Correspondents' Surnames Unknown; First Names "E" - "G,", 1958-1999, undated (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Correspondents' Surnames Unknown; First Names "I" - "J,", 1960-1993, undated (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Correspondents' Surnames Unknown; First Names "K" - "L,", 1972-1996, undated (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Correspondents' Surnames Unknown; First Names "M,", 1965-1999, undated; (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 37-38)
  - Correspondents' Surnames Unknown; First Names "N" - "O,", 1991-1992, undated (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Correspondents' Surnames Unknown; First Names "P,", 1974-1999, undated (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Correspondents' Surnames Unknown; First Names "R,", 1981-1993, undated (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Correspondents' Surnames Unknown; First Names "S,", 1973-1999, undated; (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 42-43)
  - Correspondents' Surnames Unknown; First Names "T" - "Z,", 1969, undated (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Ansel and Virginia Adams, 1963-1997, undated; (3 folders) (Box 1, Folder 45-47)
  - Adnan - Allied Travel Service, 1974-1997, undated (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Florence and Max Alper, 1957-1958 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Altman - Ansel Adams Gallery, 1947-1989 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Archives of American Art, 1965-1990 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Arthur Jaffé Heliochrome Company - Azrael, 1954-1985 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Ken B. - Bailey, 1993-1995 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Baldwin - Bertrand Russell Peace Foundation, Ltd., 1972-1994 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Brenda Bettinson, 1997, undated (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Bibliothèque Nationale - Biship Museum, 1959-1987, undated (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Bishop Museum, 1999 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Vivi Blanquie, 1959-1995, undated (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Carol Goodwin Blick, 1994-1999, undated (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Bohlig - Bollingen Foundation, 1961-1994 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Arnold Borley, 1971-1999, undated (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Dorr Bothwell, 1939-2000, undated; (4 folders) (Box 1, Folder 61-64)
  - Bothwell Family Members, 1993-1996, undated (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Brewer - Buckbee Thorne and Company, 1948-1999 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Tony Buttitta, 1966-1968 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Phil and Hall Byther, 1993-1997 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Caddes - Calcagno, 1953-1979 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - California Palace of the Legion of Honor, 1947-1972 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - California State Fair, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - California: University of California Extension, 1960-1977 (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - California: University of California at Riverside - Carmel Museum of Art, 1957-1997 (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Carnegie Institute, 1952-1955 (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Carpenter - Cavagnow, 1968-1999 (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Sue Cazaly, 1983-1999 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions - Chamberlain, 1951-1969 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Kay Chancellor, 1994-1997, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Chelette - Chico State College, 1963-1994 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Benjamin Chinn, 1972-1999, undated; (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 5-6)
  - Clinton - Contemporary Handweavers of California, 1959-1994 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Conway - Coyne, 1962-1994 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Ruth Cravath, 1949-1987 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Credick - Creel, 1994, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Liz and Loring Cunningham, 1987-1999, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Curry - Custer, 1994, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Davis - De Landrari, 1980, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Rupert De Long, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Denver Art Museum - Detroit Institute of Art, 1949-1960 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - M. H. De Young Memorial Museum, 1958-1963 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Doetry - Dunston, 1989-1997 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Evans Ecke, 1957-1997 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - ?ditions d"Art Albert Skira - Ehrlich, 1960-1997 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Embroiderers' Guild of America, Inc., 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Falkenstein - Felici, 1942-1998 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Fine Arts Gallery of the City of San Diego - Fine Arts Museums of San Francisco, 1937-1994 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Fishman - Fletcher, 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Anne Foote, 1963-1997, undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Ford Foundation, 1958-1961 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Foreign Service of the United States of America, 1950-1960 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Frances - French, 1975-1999, undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Frohnen - Fuller, 1985-1997, undated (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Galerie Billiet-Caputo - Gilbert, 1988-1993, undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Gilmore - Guggenheim, 1953-1996, undated (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Catherine E. Hallett, undated (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Hammer Museum of Art and Cultural Center, 1995-1996 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Richard H. Hancock, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Monica Hannasch, 1955-1999, undated; (4 folders) (Box 2, Folder 34-37)
  - Zoe Harris, 1972-1999, undated; (3 folders) (Box 2, Folder 38-40)
  - Harvard University - Heritage House, 1965-1999 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Helen Hipshman, 1970-1999, undated (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Hirschl and Adler Galleries, 1988-1990 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Verna and Carmer Hodges, 1989-1997, undated (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Hodowal - Hulbert, 1957-1984 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Idaho Art Association, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Inner London Education Authority, 1970-1971 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - International Graphic Arts Society, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Jackson - Johnson, 1957-1994 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Esther Johnson, 1998, undated (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Heidi Johst, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Kahana Ki'i Fine Arts Gallery - Kendall, 1969-1996 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Joan and Hal Kerber, 1987-1997 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Kerchen - Kovacic, 1951-1997 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Lagorio - Lamansky, 1960-1999 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Landor - Lee, 1958-1996 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Leach - Litton, 1977-1996 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Mahaffey - Marin Society of Artists, Inc., 1958-1997 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Marlys Mayfield, 1968-2002; (4 folders) (Box 2, Folder 59-62)
  - Marty and Fran McKinnon, 1993-1997, undated (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - McNeil - Melberg, 1978-1994 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Meltzer Gallery, 1954-1957 (Box 2, Folder 65-66)
  - Mendocino Art Center, 1961-1999 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Merhoff - Moise, 1958-1999 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Moltzen - Morrison, 1968-1997 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Jean Moss, 1978-1985 (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Moss - Mracek, 1959-1994 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Musée des Monuments Français, 1949-1960 (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Museum of Modern Art - Myers, 1956-1994 (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Virginia Napier, undated (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - National Geographic Society, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - National Museum of Women in the Arts, 1985-1998 (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - National Serigraph Gallery, 1956-1962 (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - Nebraska: University of Nebraska - Nowell, 1966-1995 (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - Oakland - Oliver, 1963-1992 (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - Oregon State College - Otto, 1956-1995 (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - Packard - Parsons, 1985-1994 (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - Virginia Parsons, 1970-1997, undated (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - Partridge - Perrill, 1959-1999 (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - Hilda Pertha, 1959-1996 (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - Phoenix Art Museum - Polk, 1993-1998 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Pomegranate Publications, 1987-1989 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Pomona College - Prints, Etc., 1956-1997 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Fred Pyrczak, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Jo Reed, 1984-1999 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Reinhold Book Corporation, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Lotte Reininger, 1972, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Reiss - Rice, 1983-1992 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Romain - Rummle, 1959-1997 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - San Diego Historical Society, 1979-1999; (2 folders) (Box 3, Folder 10-11)
  - San Diego Museum of Art - San Francisco Art Association, 1939-1987 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - San Francisco Art Institute, 1961-1999 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - San Francisco Museum of Art, 1942-1967; (2 folders) (Box 3, Folder 14-15)
  - San Jose Art League - Seattle Art Museum, 1954-1993 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Serigraph Galleries, Inc., 1948-1956 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Seri Printers - Sines, 1961-1997 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Siskin - Sonoma State College, 1964-1991 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Bette Sorensen, 1994-1998, undated (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Southern Methodist University - Stanford University, 1956-1999 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Hugo and Alva Steccati, 1986-1998 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Steiner - Stone, 1958-1990 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Sunaire - Sweeney, 1983-1997 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Jean Donald Swiggett, 1985-1990 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Taha - Taliesin, 1955-1997 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - William G. Talley, 1967-1985 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Telegraph Hill Neighborhood Association - Twenty-Nine Palms Art Gallery, 1961-1994 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Universe Books - Vaile, 1978-1985 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Van Nostrand Reinhold Company, 1973-1985 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Verner - Voller, 1959-1980, undated (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Barney Wan, 1966-1991 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Watson-Guptill Publications - Whitney Museum of American Art, 1949-1995 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Who's Who in American Art, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Williams - Wisconsin: University of Wisconsin Press, 1986-1993 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Women's Caucus for Art, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Charles Woods, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Worcester Art Museum, 1988-1999 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - York - Young, 1978-1994 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - William and Jennie Zacha, 1960-1988 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Zegart - Zellerbach Corporation, 1989, undated (Box 3, Folder 41)
- Personal Business Records, 1925-2006; Series 3; (Box 3-4; 0.7 linear feet)
  Personal business records include teaching contracts for the California School of Fine Arts, University of California at Berkeley, and the Mendocino Art Center, contracts and royalty statements for the publication of Bothwell's book Notan, insurance records, income tax records, records of a grant from the Pollock-Krasner Foundation, records concerning Bothwell's estate, lists of art work, price lists, exhibition entry cards, receipts for the sale of art work, travel receipts, and medical receipts. Of primary interest are the consignment/sales records consisting of letters, price lists, and receipts concerning the loan of art work, its temporary display, and possible sale of Bothwell's art work by various galleries including the Bay Window Gallery, the California Palace of the Legion of Honor, the Mendocino Art Center Gallery, the M. H. De Young Memorial Museum, the San Francisco Art institute Art Bank, and the Serigraph Galleries, Inc.
  - Teaching Contracts, 1956-1991; (2 folders) (Box 3, Folder 42-43)
  - Contracts for Book Notan, and Royalty Statements, 1967-1990 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Miscellaneous Contracts, 1971-1985 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Insurance Records, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Income Tax Records, 1958-1990 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Check Registers, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Card File of Oil Paintings, 1925-1954; (2 folders) (Box 3, Folder 49-50)
  - Card File of Miscellaneous Paintings, 1929-1940 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Card File of Drawings, 1926-1952; (2 folders) (Box 3, Folder 52-53)
  - Card File of Gouaches, 1941-1955 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Card File of Serigraphs, 1943-1960 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Card Files of Miscellaneous Prints, 1928-1950 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Card File of Miscellaneous Art Work, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Card File of Work Done, 1945-1953 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Lists of Artwork, 1983-1984, undated (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Price Lists for Artwork, 1947-1990, undated; (3 folders) (Box 3, Folder 60-62)
  - Consignment/Sales Records for the Bay Window Gallery, 1962-1985 (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Consignment/Sales Records for the Brunn Gallery, 1960-1961 (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Consignment/Sales Records for the California Palace of the Legion of Honor, 1945-1955, undated (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Consignment/Sales Records for Gallery Mendocino, 1990-1993, undated (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - Consignment/Sales Records for the Jan Holloway Gallery, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - Consignment/Sales Records for the Meltzer Gallery through the National Serigraph Society, 1956-1959 (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - Consignment/Sales Records for the Mendocino Art Center Gallery, 1979-1992 (Box 3, Folder 69)